--==本影片由 CMCT 团队 荣誉出品==--
更多精彩影视 请访问 http://www.hdcmct.com
影片压制: 暮雨潇潇   招募Q号: 76846146
一九六九年三月三日
美国海军为飞行员成立了一间精英学校
目的是向飞行员传授将失传的空战技巧
以确保在此毕业的一小部分飞行员
成为世上最一流的飞行员
他们成功了
现在海军称之为战斗机武器学校
飞行员则称之为顶级飞行员部
片名：壮志凌云
Revving up your engines
Listen to her howl and roar
Metal under tension
begging you to touch and go
Highway to the danger zone
Ride into the danger zone
Heading into twilight
spreading out her wings tonight
She's got you jumping off the deck
shoving into overdrive
Highway to the danger zone
I'll take you right into the danger zone
【印度洋 近期】
Highway to the danger zone
Gonna take you right into the danger zone
- 史葛 早 - 温斯 早
- Morning, Scott. - Morning, Vince.
- 威斯 早 - 长官 早
- Morning, Wells. - Morning, sir.
鬼怪骑士 斯特拉克呼叫
Ghost Rider, this is Strike.
发现不明战机 回程的战机
We have unknown aircraft. Inbound, Mustang.
循0-9-0航线飞向敌机
Your vector, 0-9-0 for bogey.
上面的是谁？
Who's up there?
美洲豹、灰背隼 独行侠和笨鹅
Cougar and Merlin and Maverick and Goose.
好极了 是独行侠和笨鹅
Great. Maverick and Goose.
笨鹅 快回答
Talk to me, Goose.
收到 我发现他了 在左侧二十度 三十英里外
Roger, I got him. Contact, 20 left at 30 miles.
以九百时速节飞近
Nine hundred knots closure.
美洲豹 你听到了吗？
Cougar, you hear that?
收到
Roger.
- 灰背隼 看到他了吗？ - 收到 雷达探测到了
- Merlin, you got him? - Roger, I've got radar contact.
我要亲眼确定他 美洲豹 你去引他上钓
I'll get a visual ID. Cougar, you hook him.
收到 我会将他煎皮拆骨
Roger, and I'll clean him and fry him.
母舰 我是鬼怪骑士 方位2-0-3
Mustang, Mustang, this is Ghost Rider, 2-0-3,
我控制住他了 他以2-7-0航线前进
I've got him inbound, bogey heading 2-7-0,
我们相距十英里 以九百节的速度靠近
We're at ten miles, 900 knots closure,
鬼怪骑士 向左十度 方位3-0
Ghost Rider, take Angels ten left, 3-0.
我们今天应该有访客吗？
Are we supposed to have visitors today?
没有 长官
Negative, sir.
- 灰背隼 看看他是不是一个人 - 收到
- Merlin, see if he's a single. - Roger.
笨鹅 你发现有尾随的吗？
Goose, you see a trailer?
没有 灰背隼
Negative, Merlin.
似乎只有他一个
Looks like he's a single.
美洲豹 我要和他正面交锋
Cougar, I'm gonna go head-to-head with him.
独行侠 别乱来 我不同意
Take it easy, Maverick. I don't like this shit.
我飞高一些 确定是不是只有他一个
I'm gonna break high and right, see if he's really alone.
独行侠 我们以一千节的速度接近
We've got 1000 knots closure, Mav.
他朝着我们飞过来了
He's coming right at us.
兄弟 你在想什么？
Okay, buddy, what's on your mind?
天啊 他们有两个人
Holy shit, there's two of them.
是米格28 没人试过这么近
MiG-28s. No one's been this close before.
他们究竟在做什么？ 什么位置？
What the hell are they doing here? What's the position?
距离二百五十英里
Two hundred and fifty miles out, sir.
二百五十英里 叫他们马上离开
Two hundred and fifty miles? Get them out.
美洲豹 你负责米格一号战机 我去追米二号格战机
Cougar, you've got MiG one. I'm going after MiG two.
他在阳光下不见了
I lost him in the sun.
该死 他在做什么？ 灰背隼 你发现他了吗？
Shit. What's he doing? You got him, Merlin?
他飞来飞去 他到我们后面了
He's coming around. He's coming around on our tail.
该死 我被他控制住了
Goddamn it. This bogey's all over me.
- 现在他们距离多远？ - 二百英里 长官
- What's their range now? - Two hundred miles, sir.
如果小于一百五十英里 就出动五号戒备机
If they break 150 miles, launch the Alert Five aircraft.
是 长官
Yes, sir.
速度三百 独行侠 消灭他
Air speed, 300. Go get him, Mav.
我准备进行导弹锁定
I'm going for missile lock.
看看能不能把他吓走
Let's see if we can scare this guy out of here.
来吧 锁定他 亲爱的 锁定他
Come on, lock up, baby. Lock up, baby. Lock up.
已经锁定他了 好极了
I got him locked. Bingo.
吓倒他了 独行侠 他夹着尾巴逃走了
We got him, Mav. He's bugging out and going home.
母舰 我是独行侠 米格战机二号走了
Mustang, this is Maverick. MiG two is headed home.
好吧 他们的位置在哪？
All right. What's their position?
距离一百八十英里 方位0-1-0
A hundred and eighty miles at bearing 0-1-0, sir.
他的导弹瞄准我们了 快点避开他
Cougar, he's got missile lock on us. Get away from this guy.
这是怎么一回事？他追着我
What the hell is this shit? He's engaging me.
该死 母舰 这是鬼怪骑士 方位1-1-7
Goddamn it, Mustang. This is Ghost Rider, 1-1-7.
我被敌机控制住了
This bogey's all over me.
他用导弹锁定我了 能允许我开火吗？
He's got missile lock on me. Permission to fire?
未受攻击前不能开火
Do not fire until fired upon.
笨鹅 他们就在我们下面
Goose, there they are, right below us.
米格战机到最佳的开火位置上了 他在美洲豹后面
The MiG's in perfect firing position. He's right on Cougar's tail.
不对 笨鹅 他早就应该开火了
No way, Goose. He'd have fired by now.
他只是想激怒我们
He's just trying to piss us off.
独行侠 快来帮我脱身
Maverick, get down here and get this asshole off me.
美洲豹 别紧张
Easy, Cougar.
带他回来 协助我进入战场
Bring it back, hard right. Help me engage.
我来了
I'm on my way.
我不能攻击这个狗娘养的
I can't shoot this son of a bitch.
看看我们能不能跟他玩玩
Let's see if we can have a little fun with him.
你说的“玩玩”就是这样？
Is this your idea of fun, Mav?
你好啊
Greetings.
看这里
Watch the birdie.
天啊 笑死我了
Jeez, I crack myself up.
这场景太精彩了 我应该当摄影师
This is a great shot, Mav. I should be a photographer.
美洲豹
Cougar...
你脱身了 米格战机一号离开了
...your tail is clear. MiG one's bugged out.
美洲豹 我是独行侠
Cougar, this is Maverick.
今天玩得真开心 是吗？
We've had enough fun for one day, don't you think?
燃料不多了 我们回去吧
I'm getting a little low on fuel, so we're heading home.
在甲板上见
We'll see you on deck.
美洲豹 燃料不多 该走了
Cougar, we're running low on gas, we gotta get out of here.
美洲豹
Cougar.
快没燃料了 美洲豹 快回去
We're on vapor, Cougar. Let's do it.
美洲豹 快啊
Cougar. Come on, Cougar.
快飞回舰上 美洲豹 快
Let's take it back to the ship, man, Come on, Cougar,
叫他尽快降落 他快没燃料了
Get him on deck as soon as possible. He's gotta be low on fuel.
美洲豹 我们要降落了
Cougar, we gotta land this thing.
我们快没燃料了 你明白吗？
We are way low on gas. You understand me?
你没事吧？
You all right, man?
独行侠 还有四分三英里 降落时作出请示
Maverick, you're at three-quarters of a mile, call the ball,
收到 独行侠请求降落
Roger. Maverick has the ball.
美洲豹 应该降落了 快点
Cougar, it is time to land, Let's do it,
笨鹅 美洲豹出事了
Goose, Cougar's in trouble.
别乱来 我们快没燃料了 快点降落
Come on, Mav, we're getting low on gas. Let's land this sucker.
美洲豹
Cougar,
该死 独行侠
Goddamn it, Maverick.
你在做什么？ 我们不够燃料这样做
What are you doing, Mav? We've got no fuel for this.
我们要去帮美洲豹
We're going after Cougar.
叫他马上降落 这是命令
You tell him to land that plane. That's an order.
鬼怪骑士 命令你降落
Ghost Rider, you are instructed to land,
马上降落
Land immediately,
你们看到附近有航空母舰吗？
Any of you boys seen an aircraft carrier around here?
我们有点小问题 那架米格战机吓坏他了
Mav, we got a little problem up here. That MiG really screwed him up.
他大概无法把战机开回去
I don't think he can make it back.
美洲豹 不要紧 跟着我飞
You're okay, Cougar. Just stay on my wing,
我会带你回去 跟着我
I'll take you all the way in. Just stay with me.
别紧张 好像逛公园一样
Easy, Cougar. Just a walk in the park, buddy.
你飞得低了点 低了一点
You're a little low. You're a little low, Coug.
伙计 快点拉升
Come on, buddy, pull up.
快点拉升 美洲豹
Pull up, Cougar.
对了 快到了
That's it. Almost there.
你比跑道低了点 还有四分三英里
You're a little below glide path, three-quarters of a mile,
请求降落
Call the ball,
收到 准许降落
Roger, ball,
美洲豹 我们太低了
We're too low, Cougar. We're too low, Cougar.
加大动力
Increase power. Some more power!
请进
Come in.
长官
Sir.
美洲豹 你应该在医护室 你在想什么？
Cougar, you should be in sickbay. What's on your mind?
我的妻儿
My wife and kid, sir.
他今天几乎变成孤儿 我还没见过他
I almost orphaned him today, and I've never even seen him.
我不知道发生了什么事 但是我很害怕
I don't know what happened up there, but I was so scared.
- 别这样 我们以前也见过这种事 - 不 长官
- Come on, we've seen this before. - No, sir.
我的压力太大了
I'm holding on too tight.
我已经受够了 对不起 长官
I've lost the edge. I'm sorry, sir. I'm sorry.
美洲豹
Cougar.
谢谢 独行侠
Thanks, Maverick.
独行侠、笨鹅 进来
Maverick, Goose, come in here.
- 发生了什么事？ - 我不知道
- What the hell's going on? - I don't know.
该死的
Shit.
独行侠 你刚才做的事很勇敢
Maverick, you just did an incredibly brave thing.
可是你应该做的是降落
What you should have done was land your plane.
战机不是你的 是纳税人的
You don't own that plane, the taxpayers do.
你真是狂妄自大
Son, your ego is writing checks your body can't cash.
你曾被降职 你三次失去当分队长的资格
You've been busted. You lost your qualifications as section leader three times.
我两次关你禁闭
Put in hack twice by me.
你曾高速飞过五个控制塔
With a history of high-speed passes over five air-control towers
和一个上将的女儿
and one admiral's daughter.
彭妮·本杰明？
Penny Benjamin?
- 你这笨蛋能在这儿真是走运 - 谢谢
- And you, asshole. You're lucky to be here. - Thank you, sir.
不说废话了 独行侠 你不是出自海军名门
Let's not bullshit, Maverick, your family name ain't the best in the Navy.
你应该比其他人做得更好 你究竟在想什么？
You need to be doing it better and cleaner than the other guy. Now, what is it with you?
我只想为国效力 当最好的海军飞行员
Just wanna serve my country, be the best fighter pilot in Navy, sir.
独行侠 别想骗我了
Don't screw around with me, Maverick.
你全凭直觉驾驶战机 也许很出色
You're a hell of an instinctive pilot. Maybe too good.
我真想开除你 但是不行 我有了另一个麻烦
I'd like to bust your butt, but I can't. I got another problem here.
我要从队中派人去米拉马
I gotta send somebody from this squadron to Miramar.
我要做一些事 我难以置信的事
I gotta do something here. I still can't believe it.
我要让你梦想成真 派你去面对一流的海军
I gotta give you your dream shot. I'm gonna send you up against the best.
你们两个会进高空利剑
You two characters are going to Top Gun.
你们会和世界上的顶级飞行员 交手五个星期
For five weeks, you're gonna fly against the best fighter pilots in the world.
本来你是第二 美洲豹是第一
You were number two, Cougar was number one.
美洲豹放弃了
Cougar lost it, turned in his wings.
你们就成了第一
You guys are number one.
但记着一件事： 你们这次要是搞砸了
But you remember one thing: You screw up just this much,
我会派你们开运输机从香港运皮子
you'll be flying a cargo plane full of rubber dog shit out of Hong Kong.
是 长官
Yes, sir.
没事了
That is all.
改天再向我汇报米格战机的事
You can tell me about the MiG some other time.
两位
Gentlemen.
- 祝你们好运 - 谢谢 长官
- Good luck, gentlemen. - Thank you, sir.
谢谢
Thank you.
【美国空军基地 加州米拉马】
海军在韩战的杀敌比率是十二比一
During Korea, the Navy kill ratio was 12-to-1.
我们一架战机就能击落敌人十二架
We shot down 12 of their jets for every one of ours.
到了越战时比率降至三比一
During Vietnam, that ratio fell to 3-to-1.
我们的飞行员太依赖导弹了
Our pilots become dependent upon missiles.
他们失去了一些空战技巧
They had lost some of their dogfighting skills.
组建高空利剑是为了教导你们空战策略
Top Gun was created to teach ACM: Air Combat Maneuvering.
也就是空中格斗
Dogfighting.
真令人兴奋
This gives me a hard-on.
到了越战末期 这一比率回升至十二比一
By the end of Vietnam, that ratio was back up to 12-to-1.
- 别跟我开玩笑 - 请拉开窗帘
- Don't tease me. - Blinds, please.
我想藉着这次机会 介绍指挥官给大家认识
I'd like to take this opportunity to introduce you to our commanding officer at Top Gun.
他是第一位获得高空利剑飞行员奖的人
The very first man to win the Top Gun trophy.
你不会在其他地方找到比他更优秀的飞行员了
You will not find a finer fighter pilot anywhere in the world.
迈克·麦特卡福长官 代号毒蛇
Commander Mike Metcalf. Callsign: Viper.
各位
Gentlemen.
你们是海军空战人员中百里挑一的
You are the top one percent of all naval aviators.
是精英 精英中之精英
The elite. The best of the best.
我们会令你们更进一步
We'll make you better.
你们每天至少要执行两项空战任务
You'll fly at least two combat missions a day,
期间你们要上课 听取对自己表现的评价
attend classes in between and evaluations of your performance.
你们在每次的空战任务中 都要面对新挑战
On each combat sequence, you're gonna meet a different challenge.
而每一次都会更加困难
Every encounter is gonna be much more difficult.
我们会教你们如何令F14战机尽展所长
We're gonna teach you to fly the F-14 right to the edge of the envelope,
你们会比以前飞得更快
faster than you've ever flown before
也会更加危险
and more dangerous.
各位 我们不是在这儿制定政策
Now, we don't make policy here, gentlemen.
那是当选的政府官员所做的事
Elected officials, civilians do that.
我们只是这些政策的工具
We are the instruments of that policy.
虽然我们不是在打仗 但要时刻保持战时状态
And although we're not at war, we must always act as though we are at war.
你在做什么？
What are you doing?
- 好钢用在刀刃上 - 我只是在想谁是最一流的飞行员
- The tip of the spear best be sharp. - I'm just wondering who's the best.
你们可能会想谁是最一流的飞行员
In case some of you wonder who the best is,
他们的名字就在墙上
they're up here on this plaque on the wall.
最优秀的飞行员及其通讯员的名字 都会记录在上面
The best driver and his RIO from each class has his name on it.
他们可以选择回来当教官
And they have the option to come back here to be Top Gun instructors.
你认为你的名字会在上面？
You think your name's gonna be on that plaque?
是的 长官
Yes, sir.
你真是自以为是 周围有这么多人
That's pretty arrogant, considering the company you're in.
是的 长官
Yes, sir.
我喜欢飞行员自大
I like that in a pilot.
记着 离开这儿后 我们都是同一队人
Just remember, when it's over out there, we're all on the same team.
各位 这儿是教大家如何战斗的
Gentlemen, this school is about combat.
当第二名是没有意义的
There are no points for second place.
解散
Dismissed.
做得好
Nice going.
替补的勋章在女洗手间
The plaque for the alternates is down in the ladies' room.
天啊 真是笑死我了
Oh, Jesus. Oh, you kill me. You really do.
不… 伙计们 “笨鹅”可是有两个O的
No, no, no. There's two O's in "Goose", boys.
真是一个不愁没目标的环境
This is what I call a target-rich environment.
你在两条腿之间生活
You live your life between your legs, Mav.
笨鹅 你也可以来这儿的
Goose, even you could get laid in a place like this.
能找到朝我说脏话的女孩 我就高兴了
I'm telling you, I'd be happy to find a girl who'd talk dirty to me.
独行侠 你想知道谁是一流飞行员？
Mav, you wanted to know who the best is?
就是他 冰人
That's him. Iceman.
因为他开战机时十分冷静 从不犯错
That's the way he flies, ice-cold, no mistakes.
磨灭你的耐性 令你沮丧 你一犯错就会被他逮住
Just wears you down. You get bored, frustrated, do something stupid, and he's got you.
滑行者 你好
Hey, hey, Slider.
我还以为你想做飞行员呢 发生了什么事？
Thought you wanted to be a pilot, man. What happened?
笨鹅 你真是个蠢才 你是靠谁进来的？
Goose, you're such a dickhead. Whose butt did you kiss to get in here?
名单很长 不过很有名
Well, the list is long but distinguished.
我的约翰逊也是
Well, so is my johnson.
你和冰人一组？
So you're flying with Iceman, huh?
- 你应该说冰人先生 - 母鹅 你好吗？
- It's Mr. Iceman to you. - Hey, Mother Goose. How's it going?
很好 汤姆 这位是皮特·米切尔 汤姆·卡山斯基
Good, Tom. This is Pete Mitchell. Tom Kazansky.
- 恭喜你加入高空利剑 - 谢谢
- Congratulations on Top Gun. - Thank you.
美洲豹的事真令人遗憾
Sorry to hear about Cougar.
他和我在飞行学校时情同手足
He and I were like brothers in flight school.
- 他以前很棒的 - 他现在仍然很棒
- He was a good man. - Still is a good man.
我就是这个意思
Yeah, that's what I meant.
- 我也是这样认为的 - 需要帮忙吗？
- Thought so. - Say, you need any help?
帮忙什么？
With what?
你想到了吗？
You figured it out yet?
什么？
What's that?
谁是最佳飞行员
Who's the best pilot.
不 我自己会想到的
No, I think I can figure that one out on my own.
听说你喜欢单独行事
I heard that about you. You like to work alone.
你一定是在幸运星之下行事
Mav, you must've soloed under a lucky star, huh?
我的意思是 先是米格战机 然后又闯进了美洲豹的战场
I mean, first the MiG, and then you guys slide into Cougar's spot.
我们不是闯进去 那也是我们的战场
We didn't slide into Cougar's spot. It was ours, okay?
有些飞行员到退役时 还没试过近距离接触米格战机
Some pilots wait their whole career just to see a MiG up close.
你们一定是既幸运又出名了
Guess you guys are lucky and famous, huh?
你想说的是臭名昭著吧
No, you mean notorious.
- 再见 - 一定会的
- I'll see you later. - You can count on it.
他们小时候一定被人虐待
They were abused children.
- 我们会有一段好时光 - 总是如此
- We're gonna have a good time. - Always.
这次应该轮到我了吧
Okay, I guess it's my turn, isn't it?
好吧 赌二十元
All right, the bet is $20.
- 二十元 - 对
- Twenty dollars. - Right.
你得对欲望有所认识才能在此刻勾搭上女人 就这么说定了
You have to have carnal knowledge, of a lady this time, on the premises.
说定了
On the premises.
来吧 这只是一场赌博
Come on, Mav. A bet's a bet.
我不知道 只是…  只是这似乎对你不太公平
I don't know, it just-- It just doesn't seem fair. For you, I mean.
但是… 她失去了爱的感觉
But... she's lost that loving feeling.
- 什么？不 她还没失去 - 她失去了
- She's lost--? No, she hasn't. - Yes, she has.
- 她还没失去…  - 笨鹅 她失去了
- She has not lost that-- - Goose, she's lost it.
独行侠 你少来了
Mav-- Come on.
该死 我讨厌她这样
I hate it when she does that. Shit.
对不起 小姐
Excuse me, miss.
别担心 我会帮你搞定的
Hey, hey, hey. Don't worry, I'll take care of this.
你不再闭上双眼
You never close your eyes anymore
当我亲吻你的双唇
When I kiss your lips
你的指尖不再温柔
There's no tenderness like before In your fingertips
你努力掩饰
You're trying hard not to show it
亲爱的
Baby
可是 相信我 我知道的
But, baby, believe me, I know it
你已经失去了爱的感觉
You've lost that loving feeling That loving feeling
你失去了爱的感觉
You've lost that loving feeling
感觉一去不返
Now it's gone, gone, gone
坐下吧
Sit down.
谢谢
Thank you.
亲爱的 我会为你下跪
Baby, baby, I get down on my knees for you
我喜欢这首歌 从没见过这种搭讪
I love that song. I've never seen that approach.
你们两个试过多少次？
How long have you two been doing this act?
- 我不知道 从… - 青春期开始？
- Oh, I don't know, since... - Puberty?
对
Right, puberty.
- 我叫夏洛特·布莱克伍德 - 我叫独行侠
- I'm Charlotte Blackwood. - I'm Maverick.
独行侠？你妈妈不喜欢你吗？
Maverick? Did your mother not like you or something?
不 这是我的代号
No, it's my callsign.
- 你是飞行员 - 是的 我是海军飞行员
- You're a pilot. - That's right, a naval aviator.
其实我们这样做只干过两次
No, actually, we've only done this twice.
结果怎样？
Oh, how'd you do?
第一次是一场大灾难 死得很难看
Crashed and burned on the first one. It wasn't pretty.
- 第二次呢？ - 我不知道 明天告诉你
- The second? - I don't know. I'll tell you tomorrow.
但暂时来看还不错
But it's looking good so far.
独行侠
Well, Maverick,
我的朋友到了 和你聊得很愉快
my friend's just arrived, so it's been great talking to you.
- 彼利 - 你好
- Perry. - Hi.
你来了 我马上过去
Hi. Here you go. I'll be with you in just a second, okay?
我可以问你一个私人问题吗？
Listen, can I ask you a personal question?
那要看你问什么
That depends.
你是个优秀飞行员吗？
Are you a good pilot?
我认为我是
I can hold my own.
好极了
Great.
我不用担心你要以唱歌来谋生了
Then I won't have to worry about you making your living as a singer.
我需要啤酒来灭火
I'm gonna need a beer to put these flames out. Yo!
好极了 真狡猾
Great, Mav. Real slick.
水手 你出海太久了吗？
It was a long cruise, was it, sailor?
太久了
It was too long.
你想怎样 就地进行吗？
What did you wanna do, just drop right down on the tile and go for it?
不 其实我是想在这张桌子上
No, I actually had-- Had this counter in mind.
好极了 一定会很舒服
Great, that would be very, very comfortable. Yeah.
可能会
It could be.
其实我来 是希望你不会为那个老鬼做错误的决定
Actually, I came in here to save you from making a big mistake with that older guy.
真的？ 那我就能和你这种年轻人好了？
Really? So I could go on to a bigger one with a young guy like yourself?
可能吧
Maybe. No?
明天一早我便要工作
I've gotta be at work very early in the morning.
你在这儿做什么？
Then what are you doing here?
你的朋友真厉害
Your friend was magnificent.
不
No.
你们也会受到独立专家的训练和评估
Now, you'll also be trained and evaluated by a few civilian specialists.
这儿有非军事人员 是因为他们对敌机很有认识
The civilians are here because they are our very best source of information on enemy aircraft.
其中最有资格的 就是教官代表 代号狐狸
One of the most qualified is our TAGREP, callsign: Charlie.
她是天体物理学博士
She has a Ph.D. in astrophysics,
她也是一个非军事人员 你们不用向她敬礼
and she's also a civilian contractor, so you do not salute her.
不过最好听她的 因为军方相信她对你们的评估
But you better listen to her, because the Pentagon listens to her about your proficiency.
- 交给你了 狐狸 - 谢谢
- It's all yours, Charlie. - Thank you.
大家好
Hello.
我们会用F5和A4模拟米格战机
We will be dealing with F-5s and A-4s as our MiG simulators.
你们大多都应该知道
Now, then, as most of you know,
F5不具备米格28的推重比
the F-5 doesn't have the thrust-to-weight ratio the MiG-28 has.
更不会像米格28那样 在低于三百节时放出能量
And it doesn't bleed energy below 300 knots, like the MiG-28.
不过米格28的反向飞行油箱确有问题
However, the MiG-28 does have a problem with its inverted flight tanks.
它不擅长做负重力飞行动作
It won't do a negative-G pushover.
最新的情报告诉我们它最多
The latest intelligence tells us that the most it will do
能够连续做一个负…
is one negative--
对不起 上尉
Excuse me, lieutenant.
有什么问题吗？
Is there something wrong?
女士 米格战机的资料不正确
Yes, ma'am, the data on the MiG is inaccurate.
哪儿不正确？
How's that, lieutenant?
- 我看过米格28做…  - 是我们
- Well, I just happened to see a MiG-28 do-- - We, we.
对不起 笨鹅
Sorry, Goose.
我们见过米格28连续做四个负重力俯冲
We happened to see a MiG-28 do a four-G negative dive.
你在哪儿见到的？
Where did you see this?
- 这是机密资料 - 什么？
- That's classified. - It's what?
是机密资料
It's classified.
我可以告诉你 但是之后就要杀了你
I could tell you, but I'd have to kill you.
上尉 我有权知道最高机密
Lieutenant, I have top-secret clearance.
五角大楼允许我比你知道得更多
The Pentagon sees to it that I know more than you.
那么这次大概不同了
Well, ma'am, it doesn't seem so in this case, now, does it?
上尉… 你当时在哪儿？
So, lieutenant... where exactly were you?
- 我们…  - 谢谢
- Well, we... - Thank you.
当他穿越云层时 我们在他后面 然后我飞到他上面
...started up on his 6 when he pulled through the clouds, and then I moved in above him.
你在他上面又怎会看到他？
Well, if you were directly above him, how could you see him?
- 因为我倒转了 - 废话
- Because I was inverted. - Bullshit.
不 他真是这样做的 很精彩呢
No, he was, man. It was a really great move.
他倒转了
He was inverted.
你倒转着和米格28一起做四个负重力俯冲？
You were in a four-G inverted dive with a MiG-28?
是的
Yes, ma'am.
- 距离多远？ - 大概两米吧
- At what range? - About two meters.
实际上应该是一米半
It was actually about one and a half, I think.
是一米半 我拍下了当时的精彩景象
It was one and a half. I've got a great Polaroid of it.
他没错 一定是一米半
He's right there. It must be one and a half.
- 是张好照片 - 上尉
- It was a nice picture. - Lieutenant.
你当时在做什么？
What were you doing there?
- 沟通 - 是沟通
- Communicating. - Communicating.
保持外交关系
Keeping up foreign relations.
我当时在向他喝倒彩
I was... You know, giving him the bird.
- 用手指表示 - 我明白 笨鹅
- You know, the finger. - Yes, I know the finger, Goose.
对不起 我讨厌它这样
I'm sorry, I hate it when it does that. I'm sorry.
对不起
Excuse me.
原来是你
So you're the one.
是的 女士
Yes, ma'am.
好吧 各位 我们要飞行了
All right, gentlemen, we have a hop to take.
这次飞行的规定高度在一万英尺 无论如何不能低于这个高度
The hard deck on this hop will be 10000 feet. There'll be no engagement below that.
出发
Move it.
上尉
Lieutenant.
别再迟到 亲爱的
Okay, well, don't be late again. You look great, honey.
谢谢 在预飞区见
Thanks, dear. See you in preflight.
上尉 你为什么不告诉我 米格战机是被你羞辱的？
Lieutenant, why didn't you tell me that you were the famous MiG insulter?
我说了会有分别吗？
Would it have made any difference?
在女洗手间里就不会
Not in the ladies' room, no.
那我们会怎样呢？
What would've?
我是这儿的教官
I'm an instructor at this school.
每八个星期就会见到 二十个雄心勃勃的新丁
I see 20 new hotshots every eight weeks.
你一定能想像得到
Now, I'm sure you can figure that out.
上尉
Look, lieutenant.
我真的很想听听米格战机的事
I'd just really like to hear about the MiG sometime.
你有权看最高机密 你可以自己看
You've got security clearance. You can read about it.
独行侠
Maverick...
我很好奇
...I'm curious.
你戏弄米格战机时 是谁在掩护美洲豹？
Who was covering Cougar while you were showboating with this MiG?
美洲豹表现很好
Cougar was doing just fine.
各位 这是你们在这的第一次飞行
Gentlemen, this is your first hop,
你们面对的战机更小、更快 也更容易控制
The jets you are flying against are smaller, faster and more maneuverable,
就像米格战机一样
just like the enemy MiGs,
计时开始 我们将记录你们的成绩
The clock is ticking and as of now, we are keeping score,
他不见了 笨鹅
I lost him, Goose.
小子 让我看看你有什么能耐
Show me what you got, kid.
- 他不见了 - 我在找他了
- I lost him. - I'm looking, I'm looking.
看到了 他在我们后面 冲过来了
I got him, I got him. He's on our tail, coming hard.
我看到他了 行动
I got him. I got him. Here we go.
好吧 笨鹅 告诉我现在的情况
All right, talk to me, Goose.
他仍然在后面 在不断接近我们 速度很快
He's still back there. He's closing in on us. He's closing fast.
小子 你可以逃 但是躲不掉
You can run, kid, but you can't hide.
来吧 杰斯特 看看我能不能逼你使出全力
Come on, Jester. Let's see if I can give you a run for your money here.
小心撞到山
Watch the mountains.
他仍然在后面
I still got him. He's still back there.
独行侠 快点想办法
Come on, Mav. Do some of that pilot shit.
我看到他了
Yeah, I got him.
来吧 快锁定它
Come on, bring it right.
笨鹅 我受够了
Goose, I've had about enough of this shit.
我要拉制动器 他就会飞过头
I'm gonna hit the brakes, he'll fly right by.
你们死定了
Okay, you're mine.
天啊
Jesus Christ.
看看你现在的境况 杰斯特
Let's see what you've got now, Jester.
让我们扭转局势吧
Okay, Mav, let's turn and burn.
他垂直飞 我也来
He's going vertical, so am I.
我们好像导弹一样 咬住他
We're going ballistic, Mav. Go get him.
他要飞越规定高度了 快抢先一步 钉住他
He's going for the hard deck. Let's get down there first and nail him, Mav.
想都别想 杰斯特 你死定了
No way, Jester, you're mine.
我瞄准你了
I got you now.
杰斯特输了
Jester's dead.
马上拉升 飞离规定高度范围 回基地
Get your butts above the hard deck and return to base immediately.
遵命
Yes, sir.
控制塔 鬼怪骑士请求低空飞越
Tower, this is Ghost Rider requesting a flyby.
鬼怪骑士 不行 航线繁忙
Negative, Ghost Rider, the pattern is full.
不 独行侠 这不是个好主意
No. No, Mav. This is not a good idea.
对不起 笨鹅 是时候飞过控制塔了
Sorry, Goose, but it's time to buzz the tower.
臭小子
Goddamn son of a bitch.
真是精彩绝伦
Great balls of fire!
杰斯特输了
Jester's dead.
- 你们赢了？胡说 - 不是大家都赢了吗？
- You won? That's bullshit. - Didn't everybody?
赢了才怪 我们都惨败而回
Hell, no, man, we got our butts kicked.
在三十秒内我们往这边飞 他往那边飞
Thirty seconds. We went like this, he went like that.
我问好莱坞他在哪儿 他竟然问我谁在哪儿？
I said to Hollywood, "Where'd he go?" Hollywood said, "Where'd who go?"
他就在对讲机上取笑我们
Yeah, and he's laughing at us, right on the radio. He's laughing at us.
不 笑你们的是我 笨蛋
No, it's me laughing, dickhead.
- 我们赢了 - 好啊
- We won. - All right.
他们也赢了呢
They won too, man.
- 我没听说 - 是真的 我们打败了杰斯特
- That's not what I heard. - No, we did, we got Jester.
不 低于规定高度的不算
No, no. Below the hard deck does not count.
规定高度？总之我们打败了他
Hard deck, my ass. We nailed that son of a bitch.
- 你们真爱自吹自擂 - 卡山斯基 你有什么问题吗？
- You guys really are cowboys. - What's your problem, Kazansky?
你是大家的问题
You're everyone's problem.
因为有你 每次飞行都不安全
That's because every time you go up in the air, you're unsafe.
我不喜欢你 因为你很危险
I don't like you because you're dangerous.
对 冰人
That's right, Iceman.
我很危险
I am dangerous.
独行侠 你和笨鹅马上脱掉飞行衣
Maverick, you and Goose get your butts out of that flight gear
到毒蛇的办公室
and up to Viper's office now.
记着 当第二名是没分的
Remember, boys, no points for second place.
- 你们要比看起来聪明 - 闭嘴
- You're a lot brighter than you look. - You shut up, okay?
- 别在意 笨鹅 - 好吧
- Don't worry, Goose, don't worry. - Okay, I will.
这两个自大狂 以四百多节的速度飞过控制塔
Two of your snot-nosed jockeys did a flyby on my tower at over 400 knots!
我要你们马上找人负责 我受够了
I want somebody's butt. I want it now. I've had it.
该死 第二次了
Goddamn it! That's twice.
一定要有人负责
I want some butts!
好吧 这也要算在账上
Well, that'll just about cover the flybys.
跟我来
Follow me.
两位 你们第一天过得真充实
Gentlemen. You had a hell of a first day.
这次任务的规定高度是一万英尺
The hard deck for this hop was 10000 feet.
你们明知故犯
You knew it, you broke it.
希瑟利军官看不见你们后 你们跟在他后面低飞
You followed Commander Heatherly below after he lost sight of you and called no joy.
为什么？
Why?
长官 我看到了希瑟利军官 他看到我飞到能开火的位置
Sir. I had Commander Heatherly in my sights. He saw me move in for the kill.
就飞越过规定高度
He then proceeded below the hard deck.
我们只有几秒的时间低于一万英尺
We weren't below 10000 for more than a few seconds.
我瞄准了他 见没有危险就开火
I had the shot, there was no danger, so I took it.
你开了火 同时你破坏了重要守则
You took it. And broke a major rule of engagement.
飞越控制塔时又犯了另一条
Then you broke another one with that circus-stunt flyby.
米切尔上尉 守则是为了
Lieutenant Mitchell, Top Gun rules of engagement exist
你和你的队员的安全而设定的
for your safety and for that of your team.
守则不可以随时更改的 包括我在内
They are not flexible, nor am I.
不遵守的话就要被开除 清楚了吗？
Either obey them or you're history. Is that clear?
是 长官
Yes, sir.
出去
Dismissed.
我真的很高兴 谢谢你
I really enjoyed that, Mav, thanks a lot.
妈的
Holy shit.
我或者可以学习当货车司机
Maybe I could learn how to be a truck driver.
你有货车驾驶学校的电话号码
Mav, you have the number of that truck-driving school
我们在电视上看到过
we saw on TV? Truck Master, I think it is.
我可能会需要它
I might need that.
评估报告显示他桀骜不驯
His fitness report says it all. He's a wild card.
他靠直觉开战机 完全无法预测
Flies by the seat of his pants. Completely unpredictable.
- 他吓倒你了？ - 是的
- He got you, didn't he? - Yeah.
独行侠 我曾经和他爸爸共事
Maverick. I flew with his old man.
告诉我 你想和他一起上战场吗？
Tell me one thing. If you had to go into battle, would you want him with you?
我不知道
I don't know.
我真的不知道
I just don't know.
- 还没睡吗？ - 是的
- You still awake? - Yeah.
有什么事吗？
What's up?
睡不着
Can't sleep.
当我知道可以进高空利剑时
You know, when I first realized that we were going to Top Gun,
我只想着拿飞行员奖
all I could think about was getting that trophy.
我要坦白跟你说
I gotta be straight with you, Mav.
现在 我只希望我们能毕业
Right now, I just hope we graduate.
我有家人 我不能浪费这个机会
I got a family to think about. I can't afford to blow this.
其实飞越控制塔不算什么
Yeah, I guess that flyby wasn't such a big hit.
我知道你很难受
Look, man, I know it's tough for you.
他们因为你是杜克·米切尔的儿子 而不让你进海军学院
They wouldn't let you in the academy because you're Duke Mitchell's kid.
你要承受这个污名
You have to live with that reputation.
我们每次飞行时 你都像是在和鬼魂开战一样
But it's like every time we go up there, it's like you're flying against a ghost.
你令我紧张
It makes me nervous.
我只有你这个亲人
You're the only family I've got.
我不会令你失望的 我保证
I'm not gonna let you down. I promise you.
回去吧
Get out of here.
在那种情形下 反向翻转会很有效
A rolling reversal would work well in that situation.
如果我做十字形翻转 就能马上开火
If I reversed on a hard cross, I could immediately go to guns on them.
但在这种速度下 太快了
Yeah, but at that speed, it's too fast.
而且太过急进
It's a little bit too aggressive.
太过急进？
Too aggressive.
我觉得应该做的 就会去做
Yeah, I guess when I see something, I go right after it.
那晚 你没告诉我你是谁
You didn't tell me who you were the other night.
你没有给我机会说
You didn't give me a chance, did you?
是你的责任
You deserved it.
我知道 不过你是想要约我吃晚餐
I know. But you were tempted to ask me out for dinner.
- 不 - 不？
- No. - No?
不 我不和学员约会
No. I don't date students.
我看得出这对你很危险
I can see it's dangerous for you.
但是如果政府相信我 你也可以
But if the government trusts me, maybe you could.
这不只是像花式飞行那么简单
It takes a lot more than just fancy flying.
今晚五点半共进晚餐
一败涂地 独行侠？
Crash and burn, huh, Mav?
滑行者
Slider...
你很臭
...you stink.
开始
Let's go.
冰人 快打
Okay, Ice, hit it.
好样的 继续
That's good. Come on.
快 来吧
Let's go, now.
独行侠 四比七 让我们宰了他们 他们都是些畜生
Come on, Mav, 4-7. Let's get them. Those guys are animals.
来吧
Let's go.
好球 好球
Good serve, good serve.
那就对了
That's game.
好吧 我们要打败他们
Okay. Fake block, stay down. We'll just take them.
来啊 你去那？ 想跑吗？
Come on, where you guys going? You walking away?
我们赢了 我们赢了
We won, we won.
独行侠 再打一局 就追成平手了
Mav. Mav. Come on, man. Just one more game. That evens it up.
- 来吧 我们能打败他们 - 不行
- Come on, we can take them. - No.
- 来吧 我们能赢他们 - 我有事要办
- No, we can, we got it. - I got some things I gotta take care of.
有事？就再打一局而已
Take care of? Just one more game.
- 求你了 就算是为了我 - 对不起
- Please? For me? - I'm sorry.
你是该内疚 来吧
You're sorry. Come on.
- 笨鹅妈妈 你的小姑娘呢？ - 就算是为了我
- Mother Goose, you pussy! - For me?
该死
Damn it.
上尉
Lieutenant?
不唱歌了吗？
What, no singing?
- 我… - 不用道歉
- Look, I'm-- I'm-- - No apologies.
你不介意的话 我想去洗一个澡 很快
If you don't mind, I'm-- I'm gonna just take a quick shower
好让你把这些弄完
while you're finishing up here.
可是我介意 我很饿
Yeah, I do mind. I'm hungry.
后来我想
And then I thought about it.
我想：
I thought:
“狐狸 你知道的 他是个聪明人
"You know, Charlie, he's a smart guy.
为什么不干脆告诉他 请他来的目的？”
Why don't you just tell him why you've got him here."
是什么？
Well?
米格战机
It's the MiG.
是米格战机
The MiG.
只有你曾经面对过米格28
You're the only pilot who's been up against a MiG-28.
我正为升职而努力工作 如果成功的话
I'm trying for this big promotion at work, and if I get it,
我不会再留在这儿
I'm not gonna be here much longer.
你似乎什么都想清楚了
It seems to me you've got it all figured out.
是
Yeah.
只是你忘记了酒
Except you did forget the wine.
对不起
Sorry.
你常常如愿以偿？
You always get what you want?
不…可能是吧
No, not always. Yeah, maybe.
那就别在意那架米格战机
Then relax about the MiG.
这首歌…
This music.
你很熟悉吗？
An old friend?
我父母很喜欢这首歌
My folks loved it.
我有很多年没听过了
I haven't heard this in years.
妈妈以前在她房里
My mother used to call down from her room
总叫我一边一边的放它
and have me play this over and over again.
我很厌倦听这首歌
I got so sick of it.
她却没有…
But not her, she....
她会独坐在一旁 一听就是几个小时
Just sit up there alone, just listening, hours.
只是在那听
Just listening.
他死后不久她也死了
She died shortly after him.
你爸爸怎样死的？
What happened to your father?
你既然有权知道机密资料
I guess I kind of figured, with your security clearance,
应该比我知道得更多
you'd know more about him than I do.
我还没知道得那么深入
Well, I didn't get that far.
这是一个谜
Well, it's a big mystery.
他在1965年11月5日开着F4失踪了
He disappeared in an F-4, November 5th, 1965.
听说是他犯错了
The stink of it was, he screwed up.
但是那不可能
No way.
我爸爸是很优秀的飞行员
My old man was a great fighter pilot.
但谁知道呢？ 一切都被列作机密资料
But who the hell knows? It's all classified.
一定有人知道的
Somebody must know.
有人什么都知道
Yeah, somebody knows everything.
所以你总是只能拿到第二名？
Is that why you're always second best up there?
你真直接
You are direct, aren't you?
对不起 我迟到了
I'm sorry I was late.
对不起 我这么直接
I'm sorry for being direct.
不用道歉
No apologies.
这会变得很复杂
This is gonna be complicated.
你去哪儿？
Where are you going?
我去洗个澡
I'm gonna take a shower.
谢谢 我在这很愉快
Thank you. I enjoyed being here.
你似乎需要再洗一个澡
It looks like you need another shower.
对
Right.
我想对你坦白
I'm gonna be honest with you.
你见过米格战机 这会对我的工作大有帮助
Your MiG sighting is really important to my work, but...
但我不是常常请学员 到家中作客的
I don't normally invite students to my house.
你是…
You're...
希望你明白我有工作在身
But please understand, I still have a job to do.
- 早上好 - 长官
- Morning. - Sir.
我很高兴我们这么坦白
I'm glad we got that straight.
我告诉她这儿有多辛苦
I told her how tough it is here.
我累得跟死狗一样
You know, my ass dragging like an old, tired dog.
我告诉她你在这儿 连一个女人也没有
I told her that you didn't even have a woman here.
- 真的吗？ - 知道她怎样说吗？
- Oh, really. - You know what she said?
他可能有八个呢
Said, "Well, he probably doesn't have one, he's got eight."
爸爸
Daddy.
独行侠 笨鹅说你和教官坠入爱河了
So, Maverick, Goose tells me you're in love with one of your instructors.
- 是吗？ - 我没说过这件事
- Is that right? - I-- I didn't tell her that.
你有说过的
Yes, you did.
- 你有说过的 - 你竟然说出来
- Yes, you did. - I can't believe you said that.
- 那是秘密 - 不
- That was a secret. - No.
敌机处在很好的位置 请定格
The bogey has good position right here. All right, freeze-frame.
是抉择的时刻了
Moment of choice.
F14处于防守态势
The F-14 is defensive.
它有机会立即逃离
He has a chance to bug out right here.
最好先撤退以及保证战机的安全
Better to retire and save your aircraft
这比处于劣势要好
than push a bad position.
狐狸 你可以随时补充
Charlie, jump in here anytime.
你在菱形区域内再多呆三秒
Now, you stay in that diamond another three seconds,
就会被敌机消灭
the bogey's gonna blow you out of the sky.
如果你选择第五区向右突围
You take a hard right, select zone five,
就能拖延时间逃走
you can extend an escape.
你作了一个很差的决定
You made a bad choice.
狐狸
Charlie.
一号战机翻了一个S筋斗
Aircraft one performs a split S?
这是你最不该做的 米格战机就在你后面
That's the last thing you should do. The MiG's right on your tail.
请定格
Freeze there, please.
你在米格战机的射程范围 你现在会想什么？
The MiG has you in his gunsight. What were you thinking at this point?
你没时间在空中思考了
You don't have time to think up there.
一想就死定了
If you think, you're dead.
用价值三千万元的战机打赌 赌得可真大呢
Well, that's a big gamble with a $30 million plane, lieutenant.
不幸地 他赌赢了
Unfortunately, the gamble worked.
米格战机无法开火
The MiG never got a clean shot.
独行侠做了一个激进的垂直飞行
Maverick makes an aggressive vertical move here,
到了顶部 他用导弹打败了敌机
comes over the top, and he defeats the bandit with a missile shot.
这次的交手是一次胜利
The encounter was a victory,
不过这是不应该再做的
but I think that we've shown it as an example of what not to do.
下一个
Next.
从没见过这么大胆的举动
Gutsiest move I ever saw, man.
接着的可以作为教科书的最佳案例
Now, then, this is a perfect example of a textbook maneuver.
上尉
Lieutenant.
独行侠
Maverick.
上尉…
Lieutenant.
上尉
我对你的飞行评估 是我的专业意见
My review of your flight performance in the TACTS was right on, in my professional opinion.
我听不到你说什么
I can't hear you.
天啊 你以为我只会鲁莽行事
Jesus Christ! And you think I'm reckless.
我飞行时就会让你知道 我以我的队员和战机为先
When I fly, I'll have you know that my crew and my plane come first!
上尉 让我把话说完
Well, I'm going to finish my sentence, lieutenant.
我对你的飞行评估是正确的
My review of your flight performance was right on.
- 是吗？ - 是的
- Is that right? - That is right.
但是我有所保留
But I held something back.
我看得出你有飞行的天赋 但是我不能在那儿说出来
I see some real genius in your flying, Maverick, but I can't say that in there.
我害怕大家会看穿我
I was afraid that everyone in that TACTS trailer would see right through me.
我只是不想让人知道 我爱上你了
And I just don't want anyone to know that I've fallen for you.
Watching every motion
in this foolish lovers' game
Haunted by the notion
somewhere there's a love in flames
Turning and returning
to some secret place inside
Watching in slow motion
as you turn my way
and say
"Take my breath away"
"my love"
"Take my breath away,my love"
- 独行侠 - 什么事？
- Hey, Maverick. - Yeah.
听说冰人的事了吗？
You hear about Ice?
- 什么事？ - 他又赢了
- What's that? - He won another one.
- 真的？ - 是的
- Really? - Yeah.
我觉得需要
I feel the need,
- 需要加速 - 需要加速
- the need for speed. - The need for speed.
各位 这是第十九次飞行
Gentlemen, this is hop 19,
会有更多战机和敌人
Multiple aircraft, multiple bogies,
训练已经过了一半 最佳飞行员奖的争夺仍然激烈
Your training is half over, The competition for the Top Gun trophy remains tight,
第一名是冰人
First place, Iceman,
第二名是独行侠 只差两分
Second place, Maverick, just two points behind,
他们来了
There they are.
在三英里外 十点钟方向 大概还没看见我们
Three miles, left, 10 o'clock. I don't think they see us yet.
好的 我看到他们了
Okay, I see them.
左边有两架A4 在十点钟方向 继续左转
Two A-4s, left 10 o'clock level, continue left turn.
各位早上好 气温是110度
Good morning, gentlemen. The temperature's 110 degrees.
天啊 是毒蛇
Holy shit, it's Viper.
毒蛇在空中 好极了
Viper's up here, great.
该死
Oh, shit.
他可能也在说： “该死的 是独行侠和笨鹅”
Great. He's probably saying, "Holy shit, it's Maverick and Goose."
他一定在这样说
Yeah, I'm sure he's saying that.
我盯住北面的敌机
I've got my eye on the northern bogey.
收到 我盯住南面的
Roger. I got the southern guy.
好莱坞 你先走 我掩护你
Hollywood, you've got the lead, I'll cover you.
杰斯特 现在分开走
Break now, Jester.
好莱坞 毒蛇不见了 先对付杰斯特吧
Hollywood, we're losing Viper. Let's just stay on Jester.
收到 我去对付他
Roger, I'm on him.
笨鹅 把毒蛇找出来 他一定在附近
Goose, find Viper. He's out there somewhere.
和好莱坞一起 我们要掩护他
Stay with Hollywood, Mav, we're covering his wing.
笨鹅 是毒蛇 他在三点钟方向
Goose, there's Viper. 3 o'clock, low.
和好莱坞一起 我们在掩护他
Stay with Hollywood, Mav. We're his cover.
独行侠 别离开我
Don't you leave me, Maverick.
好莱坞 你看起来很好
Hollywood, you're looking good.
我去对付毒蛇
I'm going after Viper.
独行侠 去你的
Goddamn you, Maverick.
独行侠 别离开他
Mav, don't leave him.
笨鹅 好莱坞没事的 我想打败毒蛇
Goose, Hollywood's okay. I want Viper.
准备 毒蛇过来了
Stand by. Viper's coming down.
该死 我们面对面了 我们竟然这样做
Holy shit, we're head-to-head. I can't believe we're doing this.
摇滚一下吧 机不可失 笨鹅
Rocking roll. Here's our chance. It's a big one, Goose.
来吧 该死的
Come on, goddamn it.
来啊 独行侠 跟着来啊
Come on, Mav, keep coming.
选定响尾蛇导弹
Okay. Sidewinder missile selected.
来吧 亲爱的
Come on, baby. Come on, baby.
回来啊 对了
Come around, come around. That's it, that's it.
天啊 他真厉害
Jesus, this guy's good.
笨鹅 他要去哪儿？
Goose, where's he going?
来啊 继续跟着我啊
Come on, come on, come on, keep coming. Keep coming.
来吧 亲爱的
Come on, baby.
该死 这小子真厉害
Damn, this kid's good.
他太接近 不能用导弹 改为用机枪
He's too close for missiles, Goose, I'm switching to guns.
快来啊 来啊
Come on, come on, come on.
坚持住 坚持住
Stick with me, stick with me.
等一下 笨鹅 看看后面
What--? Hold it. Goose, check our tail.
该死 是杰斯特
Shit. There's Jester.
成功了 独行侠输了 小子 你玩完了
Bingo, Maverick's dead. You're out of there, kid.
该死
Shit.
国防部很遗憾要告诉你
The Defense Department regrets to inform you
你的儿子因为太笨而战死沙场
that your sons are dead because they were stupid.
真刺激
Great balls of fire.
算了吧 大家回去 由毒蛇带头
Okay, knock it off, gentlemen. Let's go home. Viper has the lead.
还有三十秒 狼人 我要进来了
Thirty seconds, Wolfman, and I'm coming in.
- 闭嘴！ - 天哪 该死的
- Shut up! - God, buttnose.
我从没见过这么精彩的空战
That was some of the best flying I've seen yet,
直至你们被打败为止
right up the part where you got killed.
你永远不该离开僚机
You never, never leave your wingman.
独行侠
Maverick...
问题不在你的飞行技术 而是你的态度
...it's not your flying, it's your attitude.
敌人很危险 但是你比敌人更加危险
The enemy's dangerous, but right now you're worse than the enemy.
你既危险又愚蠢
You're dangerous and foolish.
你未必喜欢你的队友
You may not like the guys flying with you,
他们也未必喜欢你 但是你究竟是哪一方？
they may not like you, but whose side are you on?
起码毒蛇在打败我们之前 打败了冰人
Well, at least Viper got Iceman before he got us.
我们仍然有机会得奖
We still got a shot at it.
那是愚蠢的行为 我是知道的
That was stupid. I know better than that.
不会再发生这种事了
It'll never happen again.
我知道
I know.
我知道的
You shake my nerves And you rattle my brain
Thinking about your love Drives a man insane
You break my will Oh, what a thrill
Goodness gracious Great balls of fire
独行侠 快去制止他吧 他没使你难为情吗？
Maverick, would you go fetch him? Doesn't he ever embarrass you?
笨鹅 当然没有 不过 有时候…
Goose? Hell, no. Well, there was the time...
- 上将的女儿 - 什么？
- Admiral's daughter. - What?!
承认吧
Come on.
他把你飞过彭妮·本杰明的事告诉我了
He told me all about the time you went ballistic with Penny Benjamin.
是吗？好极了
Did he? Well, that's great.
他把一切都告诉我了
He tells me about all of them, Maverick.
我的小天使笨鹅 早早回家准备去教堂
How my little angel Goose goes home early for church,
你就常常带火辣辣的女人回家
and you, you always go home with the hot women.
好吧 谢谢你 嘉露
All right, thank you, Carole.
我去和笨鹅一起难为情
I'm gonna go embarrass myself with Goose for a while.
You shake my nerves And you rattle my brain
Thinking about your love Drives a man insane
You broke my will Oh, what a thrill
Goodness gracious Great balls of fire
我想警告你 独行侠很危险
I would love to be able to warn you off about Maverick,
可是我很喜欢他
but I just love him to death.
我认识皮特很多年了
You know, I've known Pete for a lot of years now,
有一件事我可以肯定的告诉你
and I'm telling you, one thing's for certain.
今晚世界上会有很多人心碎
There are hearts breaking wide open all over the world tonight.
- 为什么？ - 因为… 除非你是个笨蛋
- Why? - Because unless you are a fool,
他已经不再在情场上鬼混了
that boy is off the market.
他是百分百、史无前例地爱上了你
He is 100 percent, prime-time in love with you.
笨鹅 臭男人
Hey, Goose, you big stud!
我的确是 亲爱的
That's me, honey.
- 和我上床 否则你会永远失去我 - 告诉我怎样回家 亲爱的
- Take me to bed or lose me forever. - Show me the way home, honey.
乖儿子 和大家一起唱
Come on, brother, sing with the family.
You shake my nerves And you rattle my brain
Thinking about your love Drives a man insane
You broke my will Oh, what a thrill
Goodness gracious Great balls of fire
独行侠
Maverick...
臭男人 和我上床 否则你会永远失去我
...you big stud, take me to bed or lose me forever.
各位 这是第三十一次飞行 你们还有两星期就毕业了
Okay, gentlemen, this is hop 31, Two weeks to graduation,
最佳飞行员奖的归属仍有悬念 每一分都很重要
Top Gun trophy is still up for grabs, so every point counts,
还剩九次飞行了 分数咬得很紧 是时候来一次全胜了
Well, it's bottom of the ninth, the score is tied. It's time for the big one.
独行侠 你这次能赢吗？
You up for this one, Maverick?
这跟在公园散步一样容易
Just a walk in the park, Kazansky.
呼叫 有多架敌机 方位1-6-5
Contact. Multiple bogies, 1-6-5.
距离两英里 他们似乎想远离我们
Two miles. Looks like they're going away from us.
不 我看到他们了 在两点钟方向 我来了
Ho, I see them, tallyho, right 2 o'clock. I'm in.
我也加入
I'm in.
这个臭小子截住我了
That son of a bitch cut me off.
快 天啊 冰人 快开火
Come on, come on. Jesus Christ. Ice, take the shot.
冰人 快点让开
Come on, Ice, get the hell out of there.
我的角度不好 太近了 不能用导弹
I can't get the angle. I'm too close for missiles.
现在改为用机枪
I'm switching to guns.
冰人 你不开火就走开
Ice, fire or clear.
天啊 我在这儿也能开火
Look at this! Jesus Christ, I can take a shot right here!
我只需要多二十秒
I need another 20 seconds, then I've got it.
我来了 我已经锁定了
I'm moving in. I've got the shot.
独行侠 我们上 快
Come on, Mav, let's get in there! Come on, Mav!
独行侠不耐烦了 冰人 快开火
Maverick's getting impatient. Come on, take the shot.
再多十秒就行了
Ten more seconds, then I've got him.
冰人 快走开 独行侠 出手吧
Come on, Ice, get the hell out of there! Let's do it, Mav.
冰人 从右边走开 我要上来
Ice, come off high right. I'm in.
- 再多五秒 - 去右边 冰人 我来了
- Five more seconds. - Come off high right, Ice. I'm in.
我走开 该死
I'm off. Shit!
- 我们在喷气流之中 - 该死
- We're in his jet wash! - Holy shit!
情况不妙 该死 引擎停了 独行侠
This is not good. Shit, we got a flameout, Mav.
引擎一号停了
Engine one is out.
引擎二号也停了
Engine two is out!
笨鹅 我无法控制战机
Goose, I'm losing control. I'm losing control.
失去控制了 无法回复正常
I can't control it. It won't recover.
该死
Shit.
祸不单行 我们无法控制战机
It's coupling up, Mav! We're out of control.
情况不妙
This is not good! This is not good!
请求救援 独行侠出事了 机身在不停打转
Mayday, mayday. Mav's in trouble. He's in a flat spin.
快掉进节了
He's heading out to sea.
高度八千 七千
Altitude 8000, 7000.
现在只有六千
Six. We're at six, Mav.
我被抛到前面 笨鹅 我摸不到跳机杆
I'm pinned forward, Goose. I can't reach the ejection handle.
笨鹅 你把我们弹出去
Goose, you're gonna have to punch us out.
我摸不到跳机杆 快点
I can't reach the ejection handle. Eject.
- 我在尽力了 - 快
- I'm trying! I'm trying! - Eject! Eject!
快 小心机舱盖
Eject! Watch the canopy!
笨鹅 不
Goose! Goose! Oh, no!
天啊
Oh, God! Oh, God! Oh, God.
请你放手 你要放开他
Sir, let go of him. You gotta let him go, sir.
你怎样？
How you doing?
我没事
I'm all right.
笨鹅死了
Goose is dead.
我知道
I know.
开战机开得久了 总会遇到这种事
You fly jets long enough, something like this happens.
他是我的通讯员 这是我的责任
He was my RIO, my responsibility.
我在越战的部队 十八架战机有八架坠毁 总共十条人命
In my squadron in Vietnam, we lost eight of 18 aircraft. Ten men.
第一个人死了 你也会死
First one dies, you die too.
但还有人活着 你可以指望他们
But there will be others. You can count on it.
放下吧
You gotta let him go.
这可能是我的错
I think maybe it was my fault.
我不知道是哪儿出错
I don't know what the hell went wrong.
我想帮你 我知道你很难接受
I'd like to help. I know it's difficult.
天啊 我希望他能活过来
God, I want him back.
你需要我的话随时找我
I'll be here if you need me, okay?
天啊 他很喜欢和你并肩作战
God, he loved flying with you, Maverick.
就算没遇上你 他也会当飞行员
But he'd have flown anyway without you.
虽然他讨厌这种事 但他还是会做
He'd have hated it, but he would've done it.
我们发现这架F14的右侧引擎 卷进了破坏性的气流
We find that the F-14 flat spin was induced by the disruption of airflow into the starboard engine.
这种破坏令引擎停转 出现过多的偏航率
This disruption stalled the engine, which produced enough yaw rate
结果令机身不停打转 无法修正
to induce a spin which was unrecoverable.
气流导致引擎停转 不是米切尔上尉可避免的
There was no way Lieutenant Mitchell could either see or avoid the jet wash which produced the engine stall.
所以资询会认为皮特·米切尔上尉
Therefore, the board of inquiry finds that Lieutenant Pete Mitchell
并没在7月29日的事故中犯错
was not at fault in the accident of 29 July.
这次意外 不会记录在米切尔上尉的档案中
Lieutenant Mitchell's record will be cleared of this incident.
米切尔上尉马上复职
Lieutenant Mitchell is restored to flight status without further delay.
调查完毕
These proceedings are closed.
尽快让他恢复飞行
Get him up flying, soon.
小子 快点进入战场
Come on, kid, come on. Get in there. Engage.
独行侠 两点钟方向有一架敌机
All right, you got a bogey at 2 o'clock low, Maverick.
你的位置很好 简直是轻而易举
You got the angle. Piece of cake, pal.
快开火 小子
Take the shot, kid. Take the shot.
独行侠 你随时都可以开火
You can engage any time, Maverick.
你要去哪儿？
Hey, where the hell are you going?
情况不妙
It's not good. It doesn't look good.
情况不妙是什么意思？ 情况好到不得了
What do you mean, it doesn't look good? It doesn't get to look any better than that.
你本来可以击中他的 我们可以击中他的
Hey, man, we could've had him. Hey, we could've had him, man!
我准备好时自然会开火
I will fire when I am goddamn good and ready!
你明白了吗？
You got that?!
他仍然未恢复过来 他不愿战斗
He can't get back in the saddle. Won't engage.
只过了几天
It's only been a few days.
他可能无法恢复过来了
You know, he just might not make it back.
多让他飞几次
Keep sending him up.
米切尔
Mitchell...
笨鹅死了我很难过
...I'm sorry about Goose.
大家都喜欢他
Everybody liked him.
我很难过
I'm sorry.
你好 我是狼人
Hi, it's Wolfman.
独行侠刚刚退学了
Yeah, Maverick just quit.
对不起
Excuse me.
我可以坐下吗？
May I?
随便
Please.
和他要的一样
I'll have what he's having.
是毒药吧
Hemlock, is it?
是冰水
Ice water.
你不和我道别吗？
You weren't gonna say goodbye?
听说你得到华盛顿的工作了 恭喜
I heard you got that job in Washington. Congratulations.
谢谢
Thanks.
但是我不会不辞而别
But I wasn't gonna leave without saying goodbye.
看到你真好
It's good to see you.
谢谢
Thanks.
你要去哪儿？
Where you going?
你连机票也没有吧
You don't even have a ticket, do you?
我看过所有证据 这不是你的责任
Listen, I've seen all the evidence, and it's not your responsibility.
不是你的错 你是海军里的精英
It's not your fault. You're one of the best pilots in the Navy.
你在高空战斗是很危险
What you do up there, it's dangerous.
但是你得继续下去
But you've got to go on.
你不明白
You don't understand.
我刚认识你时 你的生活很充实
When I first met you, you were larger than life.
看看你
Look at you.
你不过快节奏生活 是不会快乐的
You're not gonna be happy unless you're going Mach 2 with your hair on fire,
- 你知道的 - 不 完了
- you know that. - No, it's over.
- 已经完了 - 作为精英中的精英
- It's just over. - To be the best of the best
就是要犯错后仍然继续努力 这对大家来说都一样
means you make mistakes and then you go on. It's just like the rest of us.
你以为我不知道吗？
You don't think I know that?
我是来帮你的
I'm here to help.
谢谢你
Look, thank you.
我需要别人帮我的话 自然会开口
But if I wanted help, really, I would have asked for it.
原来我来迟了
So I'm too late.
你已经决定离开了
You've already left.
你什么都没学到
You didn't learn a damn thing, did you?
你只学会退缩
Except to quit.
你真的很擅长做这种事呢
You've got that maneuver down real well.
再见了 皮特·米切尔
So long, Pete Mitchell.
你好 独行侠 请进
Well, hi, Maverick, come on in.
- 你好吗？ - 我很好
- How are you doing? - Good.
- 真的 你真的没事？ - 我很好
- Really? You sure you're feeling okay? - Oh, I feel great.
珍美 过来 你要喝点什么吗？
Jamie, come on. Can I get you a drink or anything else like that?
- 不必了 谢谢 - 那好吧 请随便坐
- No, thank you. - Okay, well, why don't you just make yourself comfortable.
迈克马上就下来了
Mike will be right down.
谢谢
Great, thank you.
你爸爸和我在奥利士卡尼号的 VF-51小队并肩作战
I flew with your old man. VF-51, the Oriskany.
你真的很像他
You're a lot like he was.
或多或少
Only better and worse.
他是一个天生的英雄主义者
He was a natural heroic son of a bitch, that one.
他真的没做错
So he did do it right.
是的 他没做错
Yeah, he did it right.
所以你这样开战机？ 你想证明什么？
Is that why you fly the way you do? Trying to prove something?
你爸爸的确没做错
Yeah, your old man did it right.
我要告诉你的事是机密 可能会令我丢掉工作
What I'm about to tell you is classified. It could end my career.
我们置身于一场噩梦般的空战之中
We were in the worst dogfight I ever dreamed of.
敌机像萤火虫般布满天空
Bogies like fireflies all over the sky.
他的F4战机被击中 他受了伤 他本来可以回基地
His F-4 was hit, he was wounded, but he could've made it back.
但是他留在战场 在坠毁之前救了三架战机
He stayed in it, saved three planes before he bought it.
我怎么会从没听说过？
How come I never heard that before?
州政府不会告诉家属
That's not something the State Department tells dependents
因为地图出错而发生战事
when the battle occurred over the wrong line on some map.
- 你当时在场？ - 是
- So you were there? - I was there.
你在想什么？
What's on your mind?
我的选择
My options, sir.
很简单
Simple.
你已经拿到足够分数
First, you've acquired enough points to show up tomorrow
出席明天的毕业礼
and graduate with your Top Gun class.
或者退学
Or you can quit.
这不是丢脸的事 那样打转我也会被吓倒
There'd be no disgrace. That spin was hell. It would've shook me up.
你认为我应该退学？
So you think I should quit?
我没说过
I didn't say that.
你觉得是你害了笨鹅 你对自己没信心
The simple fact is, you feel responsible for Goose, and you have a confidence problem.
我不会坐在这儿跟你说好话
Now, I'm not gonna sit here and blow sunshine up your ass, lieutenant.
一个好飞行员必须评估发生的事
A good pilot is compelled to always evaluate what's happened.
这样才能学以致用
So he can apply what he's learned.
到了高空我们就要全力以赴 这是我们的职责
Up there, we gotta push it. That's our job.
上尉 这全看你的选择
It's your option, lieutenant, all yours.
对不起 在周日打扰你 谢谢你抽空见我
Sorry to bother you on a Sunday, sir, but thank you very much for your time.
不要紧 祝你好运
No problem. Good luck.
房子出租
- 各位 - 独行侠在哪儿？
- Gentlemen... - Where's Maverick?
我不知道他在哪
I don't know where he is.
你知道他有什么打算吗？
You know what he's planning to do?
他一定很难过
Gotta be hard on the guy, though.
恭喜
Congratulations.
谢谢
Thank you.
- 恭喜 - 谢谢
- Congratulations. - Thanks, Mav.
长官
Sir.
各位
Gentlemen.
我讨厌要在派对 失去控制前把它结束
I hate to break up the party before it really gets out of hand,
但是我们有事要做
but there is work to be done.
你们有一些人要马上离开
Some of you have to depart immediately.
我们遇上了危机
We have a crisis situation.
- 冰人、滑行者 - 有
- Ice, Slider. - Yo.
- 好莱坞、狼人 - 是
- Hollywood, Wolfman. - Yes, sir.
- 独行侠 - 长官
- Maverick. - Sir.
独行侠 你到航空母舰 就会有通讯员
Maverick, you'll get your RIO when you get to the ship.
找不到的话
And if you don't...
通知我 我和你一起飞
...give me a call. I'll fly with you.
是
Sir.
【24小时后 印度洋】
各位 这是敏感事件
Gentlemen, this is bull's-eye.
通讯船SS赖顿号失去控制 漂移进了外国海域
The communication ship SS Layton has become disabled and has wandered into foreign territory.
一小时内会开始营救行动
A rescue operation is to begin within the hour.
你们的任务 就是空中支援营救行动
Your mission is to give air support to that rescue.
该区有米格战机 形势十分紧张
There are MiGs in the area, and tensions are high.
受到袭击可以还击
If you witness a hostile act, you will return fire.
米格战机有飞鱼反舰导弹
Those MiGs carry the Exocet anti-ship missile.
他们可在一百英里以外发射导弹
They can fire that missile from 100 miles away.
各位 这是真正的战斗 这是你们受训的目的
Gentlemen, this is the real thing. This is what you've been trained for.
你们是美国的精英 让我们感到光荣吧
You are America's best. Make us proud.
- 冰人 - 是 长官
- Ice. - Yes, sir.
- 好莱坞 - 是 长官
- Hollywood. - Yes, sir.
第二组 独行侠 你和灰背隼做后援
Sector two. And Maverick, you back them up with Merlin on Ready Five.
是 长官
Yes, sir.
起立
Rise!
- 对不起 长官 - 什么事？
- Excuse me, sir. - Yes.
我不针对人 但是就独行侠来说
This is not personal, but with regard to Maverick,
他是最好的后援吗…
is he the best backup--?
我知道你在想什么 总之你照着办吧
I know what's on your mind, Kazansky, just get on it.
母舰 发现敌机通知我？
Mustang, can you give me a mode-four check?
伏都一号 有两架敌机在十二点钟方向 距离十五英里
Voodoo one, you've got a pair of bogies, 12 o'clock, 15 miles.
伏都一号 方位0-9-0 雷达显示在十五英里
Voodoo one, Voodoo one, 0-9-0, radar contact 15 miles.
他们的时速是五百节
They're doing 500 knots.
收到 那就是敌机
Roger, that's your bogey.
他们在正前方十五英里 速度六百节
Got them dead ahead, 15 miles, air speed is 600 knots.
敌机速度六百五十节 我们靠得太近 离远点
Bogies' air speed, 650, We're a little close together, Let's take a wider split,
他们在一万五千英尺高空 正前方十英里
They're at 15000 feet now, dead ahead, ten miles,
正在加速
Air speed is still increasing,
八百节 正前方八英里
Eight hundred knots. Dead ahead, now, eight miles. Dead ahead, now, eight miles.
- 好莱坞 看到他们了吗？ - 还没看到
- Wood, you got them? - Not yet, I can't see them.
一定是在接近 我很兴奋
They must be close, I'm getting a hard-on.
好莱坞 我先走一步 确定他们的位置
Okay, Wood, I'm taking the lead. Let's identify them.
收到 冰人 你先走 我在你左下方
Roger, Ice, you got the lead. I'm on your left side, a little low.
独行侠已经准备好出动
Maverick's up and ready in Alert Five.
好极了
Good, good.
好莱坞 敌机仍被锁定 他在你左边
Hollywood, my bogey's still locked up, He's drifting to the left,
仍以0-9-0航线飞行
Still maneuvering course 0-9-0,
好莱坞 飞向右边会有较好的角度
Okay, Wood, let's bring it to the right, and we'll get a better angle on them,
冰人 我们有麻烦
Ice, we got a problem here.
我在雷达上发现了四架战机
Now I'm breaking out four aircraft on the radar.
不是两架 是四架敌机
Not one pair, two pair. Repeat, four bogies.
好莱坞 有四架敌机
Wood, we've got four bogies.
- 弄错了 是五架 - 是五架 长官
- Wrong! Make that five! - There's five, sir.
- 五架？ - 是的 长官
- That's five? - Yes, sir.
该死
Oh, shit!
他用雷达锁定了我们
He's got a radar lock on us!
好莱坞 快离开 快避开 去你的
Get out of there, Hollywood! Get out of there, goddamn it!
- 左转 - 被击中了
- Break left! - I'm hit! I'm hit!
我们被炸烂了 我无法控制战机
We're coming apart! I can't control it! Hold on!
- 我们在下落 - 好莱坞被击中
- We're going down! - Wood's been hit! Wood's been hit!
该死 好莱坞被击中
Shit! Wood's been hit!
伏都一号 好莱坞被击中
Voodoo one! Wood's been hit! Wood's been hit!
好莱坞被击落了
We've lost Hollywood! Repeat, we've lost Hollywood!
- 我们失去了僚机 - 叫独行侠出动
- We've lost our wingman, - Launch Maverick on Alert Five.
找出好莱坞和狼人的位置 出动救援直升机
Get a bearing on Hollywood and Wolfman and launch the rescue helicopter immediately,
- 独行侠起飞了 - 冰人 你在哪儿？
- Maverick's airborne. - Iceman, what's your position?
方位0-9-0 180英里以外
0-9-0 at 180 miles.
从左边来了
We're coming in left!
有三架米格战机在正前方 从左侧向下飞
Three MiGs, dead ahead, coming down the left side.
我去对付他们 令他们飞到左边
I'm going after them. I'm bringing it around to the left.
我们后面有四架敌机 总共是六架
We got four on our tail! That makes six of them!
你认为谁会在射击范围之内？
Who do you think is hooking in the guns range?
他开火了 右转
He's firing! Break right!
我是伏都一号 我们只能防守
Mustang, this is Voodoo one, we are totally defensive.
- 快出动戒备战机 - 他们在哪儿？
- Launch the alert fighters, - Where are they?
从160英里以外高速飞来
A hundred and sixty miles and closing in fast, sir.
叫韦勒和森坚准备
Ready Willard and Simkin off CATs three and four.
独行侠以超音速赶来 三十秒内赶到
Maverick's supersonic. I'll be there in 30 seconds.
快过来 我们面对五架敌机
Move your ass! Get up here! I'm engaged with five. Repeat, five.
我身处险境
I'm in deep shit!
韦勒和森坚怎样了？
What about Willard and Simkin?
两部发射器都坏了 不能再发射战机
Both catapults are broken. We can't launch any aircraft yet, sir.
- 要多久才能修好 - 十分钟
- How long? - It'll take ten minutes.
十分钟？两分钟内就玩完了 快想办法
Bullshit, ten minutes. This thing will be over in two minutes. Get on it!
一架米格战机在十二点钟方向
One MiG, 12 o'clock high! One MiG, 12 o'clock high!
小心后面
Watch your back! Watch your back!
右转
Break right!
该死 就差一点
Shit, that was close!
独行侠 快来帮忙
Maverick, how about some help here?
- 你在哪？ - 小子 快过去
- Where the hell are you? - Come on, kid, hang in there.
天啊
Jesus Christ.
独行侠 快援手 快进入战场 该死
Maverick, how about some help? Engage, goddamn it!
独行侠 后面有一架米格战机
Maverick, we got a MiG on our tail.
小心
Watch out! Watch out!
该死 我们刚刚飞过喷气流
Shit, we just flew right through his jet wash.
快点控制机身
Get control, Mav! Get control!
我们修正了 现在进入战场吧
Good recovery, Mav. Okay, let's get in there.
我们要帮助冰人
Come on, we gotta help Ice.
快点回到战场 独行侠
Come on, let's get back in the game, Maverick!
- 快去 - 我办不到
- Come on! - No. It's no good.
- 快去 独行侠 - 不行
- Get in there, Maverick! - It's no good.
去你的 独行侠竟然退缩
Goddamn it! Maverick's disengaging!
我早就知道会这样 该死
I knew it! Shit!
去你的 独行侠
Goddamn it, Maverick!
回去 独行侠 你不能离他而去
Get in there, Maverick! You can't leave him! Come on! Maverick!
- 你在做什么？ - 笨鹅 和我说说话
- What the hell are you doing? - Talk to me, Goose.
快回去 为了上帝
Get in there, for chrissake!
- 冰人有麻烦 - 笨鹅 和我说说话
- Ice is in trouble! - Talk to me, Goose.
快回去 独行侠 不能把他一个人留下
Get in there, Maverick! He won't last down there alone!
回去战斗 为了上帝
Get in the fight, for chrissakes!
独行侠
Maverick! Maverick!
独行侠重返战场了
Maverick's reengaging, sir.
我无法摆脱他
I can't get him off my tail!
冰人 跟着你的米格战机在我正前方
Ice, I've got your MiG dead ahead. I've got him dead ahead.
位置不错 锁定了
Good tone. I've got good tone.
锁定了 发射
I've got tone! I've got tone! Firing!
- 他们在哪儿？ - 155英里外
- Where? Where are they? - A hundred and fifty-five miles.
两架米格战机在正前方 以时速八百英里接近
Two MiGs, dead ahead. Closing at 800 miles an hour.
我看到了 我要引一架去左边
I see them. I see them. I'm gonna take them down the left side.
天啊
Oh, my God.
冰人在我们下面 他后面有一架米格战机
Ice is right below us. He's got a MiG on his tail.
他开火了 左转
He's firing! Break left! Break left!
射过头了
He overshot! He overshot!
冰人 我来了
Coming in, Ice. I'm coming in.
前面有两架米格战机
I got two MiGs dead ahead.
我看到了 一架从我们俩中间飞过
I got him, Mav. One MiG passing between us.
有一架米格战机在你左边 在三点钟方向
You got a MiG on your left. On your left! 3 o'clock!
他要开火了
He's gonna fire, he's gonna fire!
独行侠 小心北面的米格战机
Maverick, check the guys to the north! Check the guys to the north!
左转
Banking left. Banking left.
他在那儿 冰人 消灭他
There he is. Get him, Ice. Get him!
好 我来了
Okay, you guys, I'm coming in!
独行侠 有一架米格战机正飞向我们后面
Maverick, we got a MiG coming around on our tail!
- 我们要离开这 - 我不能离冰人而去
- We gotta get out of here! - I can't leave Ice.
他仍然在转向 他要到我们后面了
He's still coming around! He's gonna get behind us!
我不会离僚机而去
I'm not leaving my wingman.
我在他后面 我来对付他
I'm on his tail. I'm on his tail. I'm going for it.
我来对付他 我要向他开火
I'm going for it. I'm going for the shot right now.
收到 准备
Roger. Engaged.
雷达已经锁定了
I've got radar lock.
位置不错 我要开火了
Good tone. I'm taking a shot.
发射
Fire!
- 好棒！ - 消灭那个笨蛋了
- Bingo! - Wash that sucker, yeah!
冰人 小心 你右边有一架米格战机 他开火了
Ice, watch out. There's a MiG to your right. He's firing!
我被击中了
I'm hit! I'm hit!
我们的右引擎被击中
We're hit in the right engine!
我正在把它关掉
I'm shutting it down. I'm shutting it down.
冰人 快逃
Coming in, Ice. Coming in.
冰人 敌机仍然在你后面 我准备开火
Ice, that bogey's still behind you. I'm maneuvering for a shot.
别放过他 独行侠
Stay with him, Mav, stay with him!
- 快开火 击落他 - 冰人 我无法锁定目标
- Take the shot! Nail him! Nail him! - Shit. Ice, I can't get a tone.
快开火 独行侠 我无法摆脱他
Shoot, Maverick! I can't get him off my tail!
- 独行侠 我们又被击中了 - 不要紧
- Maverick, we're hit! We're hit again! - It's okay.
引擎仍然能运作 我们没事
Both engines are functioning. We're okay.
冰人 我数三声后向右转
Ice, on the count of three, break hard right!
三、二、一 向右突围
Three, two, one. Break right!
开火
Firing!
该死 打不中
Damn it, I missed!
别放过他 继续攻击他
Don't let him go. Keep on him, Mav. Keep on him.
我看到他了
I got him. I got him.
再来一记
Here comes a shot.
全取三分！
Scratch three!
独行侠 快避开 后面有米格战机
Maverick, move! There's a MiG on your tail! There's a MiG on your tail!
我们有麻烦了 只剩下一颗导弹
We've got a problem here. We've only got one missile left.
- 以时速110英里接近 长官 - 该死的
- Approaching 110 miles, sir. - Goddamn it.
我看到他了 他就在我们后面
I got him! I got him! He's right on us! He's between our tails!
该死
Shit.
还没甩掉他 他仍然跟着我们
You haven't lost him. He's still with us!
你在做什么？你竟然减速？
What are you doing? You're slowing down! You're slowing down!
- 我要引他飞近一点 - 什么？
- I'm bringing him in closer, Merlin. - You're gonna do what?
独行侠 是时候了
This is it, Maverick!
我要拉制动器 让他飞过头
I'm gonna hit the brakes, he'll fly right by.
该死 他会锁定我们的
Shit! He's gonna get a lock on us!
就是现在
Now!
锁定了 发射
I got a good lock. Firing.
干掉4架！
Scratch four!
母舰 我是伏都三号 剩下的米格战机都撤离了
Mustang, this is Voodoo three. Remaining MiGs are bugging out.
母舰 我是独行侠 请求低空飞越
Mustang, this is Maverick requesting flyby.
不批准 鬼怪骑士 都满了
Negative, Ghost Rider. The pattern is full.
对不起 有什么事该让我知道吗？
Excuse me. Something I should know about?
谢谢
Thank you.
臭小子
Goddamn that guy.
皮特·米切尔－独行侠
你
You!
你仍然很危险
You are still dangerous.
不过你随时可以做我的僚机
You can be my wingman anytime.
屁话 你做我的
Bullshit. You can be mine.
- 独行侠 - 长官
- Maverick. - Sir.
成为所有英文报纸的头条 有什么感觉？
How does it feel to be on the front page of every newspaper in the English-speaking world?
虽然另一方否认这件事
Even though the other side denies the incident,
- 恭喜你 - 谢谢
- congratulations. - Thank you, sir.
他们让你选择你的职位
They gave you your choice of duty, son.
任何职位 任何地方 你能相信吗？
Anything, anywhere. Do you believe that shit?
你想去哪儿？
Where do you think you wanna go?
我想当教官
I thought of being an instructor, sir.
- 到高空利剑？ - 是 长官
- Top Gun? - Yes, sir.
愿主保佑我们
God help us.
You never close your eyes
anymore when I kiss your lips
And there's no tenderness
like before in your fingertips
You're trying hard not to show it
baby
But,baby
baby,I know it
You've lost that loving feeling
Whoa,that loving feeling
皮特·米切尔 你好
Hello, Pete Mitchell.
听说精英中的精英回来了 所以…
I heard the best of the best were gonna be back here, so...
这会变得很复杂
This could be complicated.
第一次是一次大灾难
You know, on the first one, I crashed and burned.
第二次呢？
And the second?
我不知道 不过…
I don't know, but...
暂时看来还不错
...it's looking good so far.
So don't
don't
don't let it slip away
Baby
I'm begging you,please
Please
I need your love
Need your love
Yeah,bring it on back
Bring it on back
Bring back
that loving feeling
Whoa,that loving feeling
Bring back
that loving feeling
Whoa,that loving feeling
Ooh
It's just a ball of dust
underneath my feet
It rolls around the sun
It doesn't mean that much to me
I take a chance on the edge of life
just like all the rest
I look inside and dig it out
'cause there's no points for second best
There's a
raging fire in my heart tonight
growing
higher 'n' higher
in my soul,oh
There's a
raging fire in the sky tonight
I want to ride on the silver dove
far into the night
till I make you take me
on your mighty wings
Make you take me
on your mighty wings across the sky
Take me on your mighty wings
tonight
Mmm,with just a little luck
a little cold blue steel
I cut the night like a razor blade
till I feel the way I want to feel
There's a
raging fire in my heart tonight
growing
higher 'n' higher
in my soul,oh
There's a raging fire in the sky tonight
I want to ride on the silver dove
far into the night
till I make you take me
on your mighty wings
Make you take me
on your mighty wings across the sky
Take me on your mighty wings
tonight
I'm going to make you take me
on your mighty wings
Make you take me
on your mighty wings across the sky
Take me on your mighty wings
tonight
On your mighty wings
Make you take me
on your mighty wings across the sky
Take me on your mighty wings
tonight